Casey Carlsen

Enterprise Staff Architect / Persistence Domain

ttps://casey.carlsen.app @ casey.carlsen1@gmail.com

(262) 470-0824

Waukesha, WI

Summary

IT professional with comprehensive experience in software installation, migrations, capacity planning, backup & recovery, performance tuning on Linux/Unix platform for MySQL and Oracle database systems. Heavily focused on re-platforming KOHLS.COM, the #1 customer facing application, to the cloud. Used new cloud technologies to provide flexibility and cost savings to traditional application architecture while being an integral part of design, building, automating and supporting multiple microservices databases on Google Cloud platform.

Experience

Enterprise Staff Architect / Persistence Domain

Kohl's Department Stores

February 2020 - Ongoing Menomonee Falls, WI

- Evaluating internal functions, business development strategies, and IT processes and suggesting improvements.
- Creating business architecture models to reflect the organization's strategies and goals.
- Suggesting ideas to reduce costs.
- Organizing training to improve employees' knowledge and skills for future organizational growth.
- Providing business architecture and systems processing guidance.
- Ensuring the efficiency, security, and support of the organization's goals.
- Determining and implementing build versus buy strategies.

Sr. Database Administrator / Cloud Automation Engineer MySQL Database Administrator / Cloud Automation Engineer

Kohl's Department Stores

March 2018 – January 2020 January 2017 - March 2018 Menomonee Falls, WI

Technology Overview: Consul, Packer, Vault, Jenkins, GIT, RHEL 7, MySQL 5.7/8.0, MEM, NDB, Google Cloud Platform, Python, Ansible

- Extensive experience architecting, designing, and supporting highly available MySQL databases in an Google Cloud environments.
- Designed, developed and support automation tools used to deploy MySQL, NDB and MySQL Enterprise Monitor.
- Developed monitoring dashboards, alerts for cloud base databases using MvSQL Enterprise Monitor.
- Lead in the execution and development of MySQL automation framework based on Ansible and Python.
- Ensures automation handles all appropriate compliance and security requirements. Experience with infrastructure as code tools such as Ansible, Packer, Terraform, and Puppet, Python.
- Experience using CICD tools such as Jenkins.
- Experience with open source tools as Packer, Consul, Vault.
- Experience using Git and GitHub.
- Experience working in DevOps/Agile environment and strong collaboration skills.
- Supported installations, patching, upgrades, and disaster recovery for kohls.com.
- Helped with provide data migration strategy of Oracle to MySQL.
- Reviewed viability of container based database deployments on Kubernetes and OpenShift platforms.

Oracle Database Administrator

Kohl's Department Stores

January 2012 - January 2017 Menomonee Falls, WI

Technology Overview: Bash, Oracle 11g/12c, Exadata, VMWare, RMAN, RHEL 6/7

- Supported Kohls.com Oracle databases.
 - Efficient in enterprise monitoring tools like Oracle OEM.
 - Provided performance tuning when needed.
 - Helped implement database security products (Oracle Redaction, TDE encryption, custom scrubbing scripts).
 - Developed automation for Oracle installation in 1000+ remote stores.
 - Supported automation for 140 Oracle development environments.

- Experience deploying to VMware
- Oracle Standby / Failover Administration.
- Experience with Oracle Exadata/RAC systems.
- Managed and review database schema objects like tables, indexes and views .
- Acted as first and second level support for production issues providing 24x7 support and uptime.
- Provided on call support for production and development issues.

Programmer Analyst – Ecommerce Service Delivery

May 2010 - January 2012 Menomonee Falls, WI

Kohl's Department Stores

Technology Overview: Java, Bash, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Oracle

- Research application problems and provide solutions to minimize the impact to interfacing systems
- Fix problems to existing applications
- Perform troubleshooting tasks
- Conduct code reviews
- Work with development team members on new projects
- Provide On-call support for production applications (kohls.com)

Microsoft .Net Web Programmer

May 2007 - May 2010

Pewaukee, WI

The Benefit Services Group, Inc.

Technology Overview: ASP.NET, C#, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Microsoft SQL Server 2003, 2008, VB.NET

- Maintain, develop, internal and external ASP.NET/VB.NET applications
- Assist with internal computer hardware issues
- Participate in the overall planning, direction and coordination of clients' employee benefits related website document management, website design, application design and development, and database design and management
- Participate in the creation of the graphics, layouts, database design content and dynamic content of our clients' employee benefits related websites and data management programs
- Plan, coordinate and implement benefit enrollments, extranet sites and employee self-services sites, working with BSG's Analytical Services department or outside vendors if needed
- Develop and present IT recommendations by evaluating current applications and Analyze and evaluate IT applications and formulate recommendations
- Manage tasks and projects from multiple clients simultaneously while meeting designated deadlines and standards
- Identify, evaluate and resolve client issues within prescribed timeframes and guidelines

Technical Support Specialist – ID Systems

November 2006 - May 2007 Milwaukee. WI

HellermannTyton

- Maintain, develop, and grow software and printer systems
- Website maintenance
- Provide tech support for software and thermal transfer printers
- Ensure inventory is in place and backup units are available for repair

Education

Bachelor of Letters and Science in Computer Science

May 2006 Oshkosh, WI

University of Wisconsin Oshkosh

References Available on request